Guide to the Cornell University Department of Agricultural Engineering records, 1921-2009.
Cornell University Department of Agricultural Engineering records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University Department of Agricultural Engineering records, 1921-2009.
21-11-2379
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences. Department of Agricultural Engineering.
12.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, legal documents, photographs, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, drawings, legal documents, black and white negatives, prints, films and department history.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Department status came in 1909 with the name Department of Farm Mechanics. In 1913 it was renamed the Department of Rural Engineering and in 1930 the name changed to Department of Agricultural Engineering. This name stayed until 1988 when it was changed to the Department of Agricultural and Biological Engineering and in 2001 it changed to the Department of Biological and Environmental Engineering.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, drawings, legal documents, and other materials relating to patent applications for a cabbage harvester (1964) and an apple harvester (ca. 1970-1983), by Gerald Rehkugler, William F. Millier, Stanley Shepardson, and others. Also black and white negatives and prints (ca. 3x5") of grape harvesters and other experimental farm equipment.
Includes extension reports, plans of work, department reviews (1979, 1985), engineering drawing sheets, and design plans for various equipment.
Also films, photographs, deceased faculty files and other material relating to the department's history.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences. Department of Rural Engineering.
Subjects:
Agricultural engineering.; Farm equipment.; Agricultural machinery.; Apple industry.; Cabbage industry.; Grape industry.; Grapes -- Harvesting.
Form and Genre Terms:
Patents.; Photographs.; Negatives.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
See also Clesson Nathan Turner papers #21-11-810
Publications can be found online here: http://ecommons.cornell.edu/handle/1813/7642
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Reports and Reviews
  - Agricultural Engineering - SEA/CR Review, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Agricultural Engineering - CSRS Review, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Rural Engineering Extension Report, 1921-1922 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Rural Engineering Extension Report, 1922-1923 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Rural Engineering Extension Report, 1923-1924 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Rural Engineering Extension Report, 1924-1925 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Rural Engineering Extension Report, 1925-1926 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Rural Engineering Extension Report, 1926-1927 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Rural Engineering Extension Report, 1927-1928 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Rural Engineering Extension Report, 1928-1929 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1929-1930 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1930-1931 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1931-1932 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1932-1933 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1940-1941 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1946-1947 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 6-7)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1951-1952 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Report, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1932; 1933; 1934-1935 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1935-1936; 1936-1937; 1945 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1946-1948 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1950; 1953; 1954 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1955; 1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1957; 1958 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1959; 1960 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1962-1964 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1965-1967 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plan of Work, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plan of Work, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plan of Work, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Emergency Farm Machinery Repair Reports, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Plans of Work, 1943-1945 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Agricultural Engineering Annual Extension Report, 1953-1955 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Agricultural Engineering Annual Extension Report, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Agricultural Engineering Annual Extension Report, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Agricultural Engineering Annual Extension Report, 1957-1958 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Agricultural Engineering Annual Extension Report, 1958-1959 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Agricultural Engineering Annual Extension Report, 1959-1960 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Agricultural Engineering Annual Extension Report, 1961-1963 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Agricultural Engineering Annual Extension Report, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Progress Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Agricultural Engineering Extension Progress Reports, 1970-1974 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - SEA/CR Review, 1979-10-22-1979-10-15 (Box 3)
    Large spiral-bound manual, "Comprehensive review."
  - CSRS Review, 1985-10-21-1985-10-24 (Box 3)
    Large spiral-bound manual, "Cooperative State Research Service Review"
- Series II. Department Files
  - Deceased Faculty
    This subseries generally includes biographical information, correspondence, photos, publication and presentation lists, promotional materials for tenure, retirement files, annual reviews, sabbatical notes, trip reports, and awards received.
    - Black, Richard D., 1964-1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Includes photographs.
    - Campbell, Joseph Kearns (1), 1967-1997 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Campbell, Joseph Kearns (2) (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Campbell, Joseph Kearns (3), 1969-1991 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Campbell, Joseph Kearns (4) Retirement, 1990-1995 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Campbell, Joseph Kearns (5), 1970-1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Campbell, Joseph Kearns (6) Sabbatical, 1973-1993 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Campbell, Joseph Kearns (7), 1988-1993 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Campbell, Joseph Kearns (8), 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Campbell, Joseph Kearns (9), 1983-1988 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Davis, Hollis R., 1961-1994 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Eaton, Edward O., 1959-2012 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Foss, Edward W., 1957-1993 (Box 13, Folder 13)
      Departmental correspondence.
    - French, Orval C (1), 1937-1999 (Box 13, Folder 14)
      Includes photos and newspaper clippings.
    - French, Orval C (2), 1954-1973 (Box 13, Folder 15)
      Includes nomination as McCormick Medalist.
    - Gray, Harold F., 1949-1984 (Box 13, Folder 16)
      Includes photograph.
    - Guest, Richard (1) Retirement, 1991-1997 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Guest, Richard (2), 1963-1995 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Guest, Richard (3), 1958-1990 (Box 13, Folder 19)
      Includes newspaper clippings.
    - Guest, Richard (4), 1983-1990 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Gunkel, Wesley W. (1) Retirement, 1991-2000 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Gunkel, Wesley W. (2), 1964-1994 (Box 13, Folder 22)
      Includes a set of B and W photographs, relating to research.
    - Gunkel, Wesley W. (3), 1963-1991 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Gunkel, Wesley W. (4), 1986-1989 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Gunkel, Wesley W. (5), 1954-1985 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Irwin, Lynne H, Lynne H. - Teaching/Advising (1), 1967-1994 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - Proposals/Funding/Grants (2), 1998-2005 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - Awards/Nominations (3), 1982-1990 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - PR (4), 1981-2004 (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Includes brochures for workshops, newspaper articles.
    - Irwin, Lynne H - Start Up (5) (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - HR/Salary (6), 1972-2005 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - CV/Bio (7) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - Research/Publications (8), 1974-1996 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - Sabbatical/Leaves (9), 1979-2001 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - Course Evaluations (10) (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - Promotions/Reappointments (11), 1974-1991 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - Mentoring Committee (12), 1974-2004 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Irwin, Lynne H - LTAP (13), 2007-2008 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Irwin, Lynne H, Lynne (14), 2015-2016 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      Includes LTAP proposal in full.
    - Irwin, Lynne H, Lynne (15), 1988-1999 (Box 14, Folder 18)
      Includes report of the Technology Transfer Center.
    - Irwin, Lynne H, Lynne (16), 1987-1990 (Box 14, Folder 19)
      Includes evaluation report of the Technology Transfer Program.
    - Irwin, Lynne H, Lynne (17), 1974-1987 (Box 14, Folder 20)
      Includes Final Report of Technology Transfer Center
    - Lorenzen, Robert T., 1984-2011 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Ludington, David C. (1) Evaluations, 1991-1994 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Ludington, David C. (2) Evaluations, 1979-1992 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Ludington, David C. (3), 1968-2011 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Ludington, David C. (4), 1953-1994 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Ludington, David C. (5) Sabbatical, 1966-1991 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Lund, Daryl, 1988-1995 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Millier, William F., 1949-2002 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Spanswick, Roger M. (1) CV/Bio (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Spanswick, Roger M. (2) Research publications (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Spanswick, Roger M. (3) Teaching/Advising, 2002-2003 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Student evaluation of BEE 494.2.
    - Spanswick, Roger M. (4) Awards/Nominations (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Includes election to Fellowship of World Innovation Foundation.
    - Spanswick, Roger M. (5) PR, 2002-2004 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Inclusion in list of highly cited researchers, election to AAAS Fellow.
    - Spanswick, Roger M. (6) BEE Affiliation, 2000-2004 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Spanswick Affiliation Votes (7) (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Spanswick, Roger M. (8) Promotions/Reapps, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Stan Shepardson Memorial Statement - R. B. Furry, 1946-2005 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      Includes photographs, slides, office name plate, faculty memorial booklet.
    - Terry, Cyrl W., 1953-1994 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Includes, newspaper clippings, and US Navy photographs.
    - Turner, Clesson N., 1945-1999 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Winkelblech, Carl S. (1), 1966-2009 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Winkelblech, Carl S. (2), 1954-1996 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Department history
    - ABEN Budget Conference, 1997-04-28-1998 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      Includes ABEN program review.
    - Cornell Chronicle (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - CALS Centennial (Box 15, Folder 16)
      Includes magazine commemorating CALS Centennial "A Century of Leadership".
    - Agriculture and Biological Engineering Department Outreach, 1996-1997 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      Includes descriptions of extension activities/programs carried out by faculty and staff.
    - Undergrad Programs, 2006-2007 (Box 15, Folder 18)
      Includes Biological and Environmental Engineering Department booklet of courses.
    - NYS Dairy Stats, Annual Summary, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      Booklet, NYS Department of Agriculture and Markets.
    - Research, 1887-1997 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      Includes 3 booklets: Ag Eng research 1978, Centennial of Hatch Act 1887-1987, Research in Eng and Applied Science, 1984.
    - Academic Review, 2002-04-08-2002-04-13 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      Includes agriculture and Biological Engineering academic review; includes mission, evaluation, recommendations.
    - Publications (1), 1957-1993 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      Includes Alumni News, agricultural progress reports.
    - Publications (2), 1956-1970 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      Includes a variety of department publications with news, research.
    - Publications (3), 1957-1959 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Microcomputing project document (Box 15, Folder 25)
      Description of program for use of microcomputers in undergraduate curriculum.
  - Engineering drawing sheets and schematic drawings (Box 3)
    - "Engineering Drawing Sheets Series D", 1941 (Box 3)
      McGraw-Hill
    - Thermostatically Controlled Exhaust Positioning Louvre, Sheet 2 of 2, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
      7 copies of drawing. Design by W. F. Millier 1949, Drawn by A. R. Barton 1950.
    - Total and Latent Heat Production of Cattle, Undated (Box 4)
      1 schematic drawing
    - Untitled drawing, louvers and exhaust, Undated (Box 4)
      Smallest of all the drawings, white paper.
    - Psychrometric Density Chart, Undated (Box 4)
    - Thermostatically Controlled Exhaust Positioning Louvre, Sheet 1 of 2, Undated (Box 4)
    - Chart No 11, Psychrometric Chart for Normal Temperatures, Undated (Box 4)
    - Chart No 12, Psychrometric Chart for Low Temperatures, Undated (Box 4)
    - Apple Harvester, Undated (Box 4)
      Set of schematic drawings: "Cornell Multi-Level Fresh Market Apple Harvester"
    - Experimental Recoil-Impulse Trunk Shaker, 1981 (Box 4)
      Multiple schematic drawings, laminated, "Designed by Ing Johan Van De Werken".
- Series III. Media
  - Films
    - Canadian Plow Math, Jennings 1929, 1929; F-1909 (Box 9)
    - Braking of an Agr. Tractor! By K. Ryan, C.W. Terry, 1959-04; F-1914 (Box 10)
      "Given at summer ASAE meeting 1960"
    - Principles of Refrigeration, 1960; F-1887 (Box 8)
    - Untitled, 1974; F-1910 (Box 9)
      Reel is inside a "rush delivery" box, sent from Dept of Ag Eng to WRS Motion Picture Lab.
    - Tandem Parlor Astarc, 1975-04; F-1897 (Box 8)
    - Impact Shaking, 1979-1980; F-1917 (Box 10)
      Label: "Dr J. Robert Cooke"
    - Checking the System, Part 1: General Procedure, Undated; F-1886 (Box 8)
    - Principles of Refrigeration, F-1887 (Box 8)
    - Ed Eaton, Chisels and Gouges, Undated; F-1888 (Box 8)
    - Planes, Undated; F-1889 (Box 8)
      Label also says "Film Library, Roberts Hall".
    - Reel IV, Undated; F-1890 (Box 8)
      Handwritten title, illegible, "Test on --"
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1891 (Box 8)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1892 (Box 8)
    - Potato Spray Reel I, Undated; F-1893 (Box 8)
    - Potato Spray Reel II, Undated; F-1895 (Box 8)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1894 (Box 8)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1896 (Box 8)
    - Boring and Drilling Tools, Undated; F-1898 (Box 8)
    - Farm Machinery 2, Undated; F-1899 (Box 8)
    - Henry R. Head, Ithaca NY, Undated; F-1900 (Box 8)
      Inner reel labelled: "Combines 2".
    - Ed. Eaton, Ag, Engineering, Undated; F-1901 (Box 8)
    - Agricultural Engineering: Profession With A Future, Undated; F-1911 (Box 9)
      US Dept of Ag, Color, 14 min.
    - Checking the Electrical System, Undated; F-1903 (Box 9)
    - Checking the Electrical System Part II, Undated; F-1902 (Box 9)
    - Checking and Adjusting the Expansion Valve, Undated; F-1905 (Box 9)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1906 (Box 9)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1907 (Box 9)
    - Walking Plow, Undated; F-1908 (Box 9)
    - Mechanical Harvesting Research, Undated; F-1920 (Box 10)
      "Property of Everett D. Markwardt"
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1921 (Box 10)
    - Apple Harvesting, Undated; F-1912 (Box 10)
    - Mechanical Harvesting, Undated; F-1913 (Box 10)
      Label reads: "Original silent "A" roll color "Mechanical Harvesting" belonging to Stan Shepherdson.
    - The Investment of Many Print #14, Undated; F-1922 (Box 10)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1930 (Box 10)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1919 (Box 10)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1918 (Box 10)
      Handwritten post-it note: "Film from Dr. Millier for archives. PS We should show this at a faculty Mtg. I'll make the popcorn!"
    - Apple Harvest In Tree Collection, Undated; F-1915 (Box 10)
      Label: "Dr. J. Robert Cooke"
    - Untitled, Undated; F-1916 (Box 10)
  - Film Clips
    - 1st Ball, 1950; F-2025 (Box 11)
      B. A. Jennings
    - Untitled, 1950; F-2028 (Box 11)
      C. W. Terry
    - Cherry Harvest (Sodus), 1959; F-2000 (Box 11)
    - Harvester, 1959; F-2022 (Box 11)
    - Extra Film From Dorn Farm Operation (1), 1959; F-2031 (Box 11)
      Terry, Ag. Eng.
    - Extra Film From Dorn Farm Operation (2), 1959; F-2032 (Box 11)
      Terry, Ag Eng.
    - Cherry Harvest Sodus 1959, 1959; F-2051 (Box 11)
    - Cornell Harvester, 1960; F-2011 (Box 11)
    - Harvest Stopper at Serturga, 1960; F-2018 (Box 11)
    - Good Film of Cherry Harvest, 1960; F-2038 (Box 11)
      Prof. E. D. Markwardt
    - Untitled, 1960; F-2039 (Box 11)
    - Apple Harvesting, 1960; F-2044 (Box 11)
    - Potato Harvesting, Apple Harvesting, 1960; F-2047 (Box 11)
    - Film Pieces Cut Out of Apple Harvesting Film, 1961; F-2033 (Box 11)
    - 1 Roll of Harvesting (Not Fast), 1961; F-2035 (Box 11)
    - Cherry Harvest, 1961; F-2041 (Box 11)
      Cut From Before Last Scene of Film. (Close up views).
    - Decelerator Stops, 1961; F-2049 (Box 11)
    - Markwardt Ag Eng, 1962-02-23; F-2017 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1962; F-2005 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1962; F-2021 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1962; F-2023 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1962; F-2026 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1962; F-2043 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1962; F-2048 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1962; F-2050 (Box 11)
    - Decelerator (dark), 1963; F-2024 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1963; F-2009 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1963; F-2056 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1964; F-2007 (Box 11)
    - 1964 Apple Harvester, 1964; F-2066 (Box 11)
    - "Apple Harvesting", 1965; F-2006 (Box 11)
    - Harvester, 1965; F-2003 (Box 11)
    - Apple Harv. (Last), 1965; F-2037 (Box 11)
    - Catching Apples, 1965; F-2040 (Box 11)
    - Apple Harvesting, 1965; F-2046 (Box 11)
    - Apple Harvester, 1966; F-2004 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1966; F-2029 (Box 11)
      Lopez
    - Meyers Operation, 1966; F-2052 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1966; F-2053 (Box 11)
    - Tomato Harvesting, 1966; F-2054 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1966; F-2057 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1967-11-03; F-2027 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1967; F-2010 (Box 11)
      Kenneth E. Ryan
    - Composite Harvester Film and Tomato Harvester, 1967; F-2016 (Box 11)
    - McConnell 500 Planter, 1967; F-2020 (Box 11)
    - Harvester, 1967; F-2034 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1967; F-2036 (Box 11)
    - Airplane Spraying, Tomato Harvest F.M.C., 1967; F-2045 (Box 11)
    - Large Cat. Frame and Trunk Shaker, 1967; F-2059 (Box 11)
    - E. Markwardt 1968 Cont. Harv. Duplicate, 1968; F-2015 (Box 11)
    - Cabbage Harvester, 1968; F-2019 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1968; F-2042 (Box 11)
      Completely unopened box of film.
    - Untitled, 1968; F-2058 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1971; F-2030 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, 1971; F-2060 (Box 11)
    - FMC Tomato Harvester, Undated; F-1999 (Box 11)
    - Leader and Blank Film for Editing, Undated; F-2001 (Box 11)
    - PR65519, Undated; F-2002 (Box 11)
    - Rice, Undated; F-2008 (Box 11)
    - Apple Sorting Machine, Undated; F-2012 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2013 (Box 11)
    - Furnow, Foster Lab., Undated; F-2014 (Box 11)
    - Cottage Harvest, Undated; F-2055 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2061 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2062 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2063 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2064 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2065 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, Undated; F-2067 (Box 11)
  - Sound recordings and videos
    - Agricultural Engineers In Pictures, Undated; TR-15913 (Box 11)
      Wallensoch
    - Agricultural Engineering Alumni Breakfast, 1979-12-1; TR-15914 (Box 11)
      Held in New Orleans
    - Tractor Rollover Film 16mm Color Print, Undated; TR-15915 (Box 11)
    - Untitled, Undated; V-9985 (Box 11)
    - Research Experience for Undergraduates, 2005-08-03; DVD-2670 (Box 11)
  - Digital files
    - Jim Bartsch on J.K. Campbell, 1986-04-18 (Box 9)
      Data reel (old computer programs)
- Photographs
  - "Troy Photo", 1912 (Box 3)
    Black and white photo, approx 16" x 10.75". Reverse description: "Troy Photo. Clara Browning, class of 1912 is the woman on the right without a hat on. She married Professor Goodman." Mounted on cardboard that is partially ripped in upper and lower right corners.
  - Agricultural Machine Guarding, Undated (Box 8)
    Set of slides, US Dept of Labor.
  - Farm Safety - A Hazard Survey, Undated (Box 8)
    Set of slides